John A Robles Perez john.robles1@upr.edu 1+(787)-460-6052



SUMMARY

More than 4 years programming and application development experience. I am a full stack developer and a freelancer. As also, a web and mobile application developer. Moreover, I am looking for a job or COOP where I can develop my skills as a software engineering or developer.

COMPUTER SKILLS

Languages and Software

- Proficient in: Java, JavaScript, Python, C, HTML, CSS.
 Source Control: Git, GitHub, GitLab
- Frameworks: React.js, React Native, Spring, Material UI, Flask, Bootstrap
- Run Time Environment: Node.js, Java Runtime Environment (JRE)
- Database: PostgreSQL, SQLite, MySQL.
 Platforms: Windows, Linux, Mac OS.

EXPERIENCE

Backend System with PostgreSQL database using Python

January 2021 - May 2021

 Twitter-Style Service with PostgreSQL database hosted in Heroku focused to manage many users functions as block users, unblock users, post a new message, reply message, share message, like message, get notifications and others.

Web and Mobile Application Developer with React and React native using JavaScript

January 2020 - May 2021

 Beach Quality Report Mobile App, Food Menus Mobile App, Shop Store Mobile App, Great Places Mobile App, Titular Mobile App, Pokémon Calculator Mobile App, Doctor Appointment Web App, Food4Help Web App

Intern Web Developer

Summer 2019

Watric Company

• Fixing server of website, adding new information, sections, and sales.

Undergraduate Investigation - Applied Optimization with 3D Printing

January 2018 - May 2019

University of Puerto Rico - Mayaguez

Manufacturing related systems – design systems to aid manufacturing. Personal Scanning for 3D printing – usage of cellphones to translate real forms into 3D models for 3D printing. Obtain human features to prototype shells. Design, develop and test human – aid 3D printed components. Build ear prothesis with flexible material.

Projects using Java

August 2017 – February 2019

 Polynomial Operations, Polynomial Advanced Language (PAL), Car Dealer Backend Service, and many games.

EDUCATION

University of Puerto Rico - Mayaguez

2014 - Present

Mayaguez, Puerto Rico

Software Engineering, BS.